# **NGUYEN VAN HAI**

DevOps Engineer



#### **Contact information**

February 04, 1994

Male

+84985505073

□ nguyenvanhai12cth02@gmail.com

★ 4A/43 D1 Street, Ward 25, Binh Thanh District, Ho Chi Minh City

https://www.linkedin.com/in/hai-nguyen-3b7073101/

#### **Skills**

#### Language

English

#### Computer

K8S, Ansible, Docker, Terraform, Git, Cloud, Linux, Networking, Security...

#### **Interests**

I like to research new technologies about Cloud, DevOps, Microservices, Automation...

# **Objective**

With over seven years of experience in cloud computing, with extensive experience and expertise spanning the areas of networking, security, systems, microservices, and customer consulting skills. Taking advantage of my experiences, skills, and learning spirit. I hope to be able to bring many best solutions and help customers achieve more success in their digital transformation journey. Thereby helping the company achieve more profits and increase the number of customers.

### **Certificates**

Oct 2021: Certified Kubernetes Security Specialist (CKS)

May 2021: Certified Kubernetes Administrator (CKA)

May 2021: Certified Kubernetes Application Developer (CKAD)

Dec 2020: Certified Rancher Operator: Level One

Jun 2020: AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate

Nov 2018: CCIE Routing and Switching – Written (Expired 2021)

Jul 2018: VMware Certified Professional 6 - Data Center

Virtualization

# Work experience

#### Senior Cloud Engineer (2 yr 4 mos)

Aug 2020 -- Present

IIJ Global Solutions Vietnam Co., Ltd

- To ensure stability, operate and maintain infrastructures for the FPT HIGIO Public Cloud in two regions (HCM and Hanoi).
- Conduct research and development on new products for the HIGIO Cloud ecosystem.
- Research, test, and deploy an Amazon EKS cluster, as well as Route 53, ALB, NLB, Ingress, SSL, and block storage for applications.
- Training about Kubernetes fundamentals for the technical team.
- Consulting and building solution architectures for customers based on FPT HI GIO Public Cloud and HIGIO Private Cloud VMware Edition Platform such as Bank SinoPac, Ung Buou Hospital, KBank Thailand, Mai Linh Express, SCBank, and King Coffee (PoC), Dong Tam ...
- Layer 3 supports handling and investigating emergencies related to network and security of Cloud Infrastructure.
- Execute maintenance planning, reviewing, and evaluating procedures.
- Write Ansible Playbooks to manage the account (CRUD) and backup/restore the configuration of Switch devices.
- Deploy and manage the Patching service, which manages and

update all system's patches.

Project: Build a Kubernetes as a Service Platform (HIGIO KaaS):

**Duration:** 9 months (Aug 2020- May 2021)

**Technologies Used:** Rancher, Citrix ADC, VMware vSphere, Fortigate, Switch Cisco, Dell.

- Collaborate with the team to R&D, build the architecture and deploy the HIGIO KaaS based on Rancher.
- Research and integration of Citrix ADC Ingress Controller support for multi-tenancy into the HIGIO KaaS platform.
- Deploy firewall clusters to protect the systems and provide an Internet gateway for K8S clusters.
- Test and analyze cases like deploying k8s clusters, applications, Ingress, and load balancers.

The following is how the link introduces the product: https://www.iij.ad.jp/en/news/pressrelease/2021/0331.html

## Network & Security Cloud Administrator (3 yrs 8 mos)

Nov 2016-Jul 2020

FPT Telecom International Co., Ltd (FTI)

- Operate and maintain the Network Infrastructures of FPT HI GIO Public Cloud HCM site & HNI site to ensure stability.
- Manage and allocate network resources, and make a plan for maintenance, changing configurations, upgrading, and expanding network infrastructure.
- Work process compliance and system changes based on ISO 27017-2015 standards for cloud services.
- Advising customers on cloud services, designing network architecture, providing connectivity services such as MPLS L2 and L3, VPN S2S, and VPN client-to-site, xConnect, and enabling direct access to the cloud system.
- Work with the sales team to organize and publicize maintenance schedules affecting clients' systems.

### System Engineer (8 mos)

Feb 2016-Oct 2016

FPT Telecom Joint Stock Company (FPT Telecom)

- Research, build solutions, and deploy for cloud project based on the OpenStack platform.
- Research components such as Nova, Neutron, Cinder, Ceph, Docker container, Python scripts.

#### **Education**

### Nguyen Tat Thanh University

Dec 2012-Feb 2016

Major: Computer Network

Certificate: The Degree of Associate